<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" version="2.0"><channel><title><![CDATA[jean.arjean]]></title><description><![CDATA[jean.arjean's personal webiste!!! Hooray!]]></description><link>https://jeanarjean.com</link><generator>RSS for Node</generator><lastBuildDate>Mon, 31 May 2021 12:27:41 GMT</lastBuildDate><item><title><![CDATA[Finish the Week with Something - Week 10]]></title><description><![CDATA[Summary Ran, bought a bicycle, setup the docker image publishing pipeline. Running Ran 4 days in a row last week, managed to push my…]]></description><link>https://jeanarjean.com/blog/2021-05-31-finish-the-week-with-something-week-10/</link><guid isPermaLink="false">https://jeanarjean.com/blog/2021-05-31-finish-the-week-with-something-week-10/</guid><pubDate>Mon, 31 May 2021 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><content:encoded>&lt;h1&gt;Summary&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Ran, bought a bicycle, setup the docker image publishing pipeline.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1&gt;Running&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Ran 4 days in a row last week, managed to push my personal best to 5km in 25 minutes which brings my pace to 5min/km.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1&gt;Cycling&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Bought a bike, it&apos;s god damn fast, it&apos;s very fun, will probably use it all summer. Climbed Mount Royal yesterday, was
really fucking fun, really makes me want to be more active, it seems the day I don&apos;t bike/run, I&apos;m an unhappy sloth (
although most sloths look happy, maybe I should learn something from them).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1&gt;Devops&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Set up a CD pipeline to release the docker image into a private Cloud Ocean docker registry.&lt;/p&gt;</content:encoded></item><item><title><![CDATA[Finish the Week with Something - Week 9]]></title><description><![CDATA[Summary I have decided on goals for the upcoming weeks. I've decided to run a half marathon, setup the development/production environment…]]></description><link>https://jeanarjean.com/blog/2021-05-24-finish-the-week-with-something-week-9/</link><guid isPermaLink="false">https://jeanarjean.com/blog/2021-05-24-finish-the-week-with-something-week-9/</guid><pubDate>Tue, 25 May 2021 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><content:encoded>&lt;h1&gt;Summary&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I have decided on goals for the upcoming weeks. I&apos;ve decided to run a half marathon, setup the development/production environment for my side projects.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1&gt;Running&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Having a morning run definitely improves my mood during the day, combining this with a cold shower and waking up
whenever my body feels like it (usually between 7 and 8am) has improved my quality of life quite a lot. I feel a lot
less tired during the day and my brain manages to be productive most of the day where it used to have down times where
it would feel too tired to progress.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I&apos;ve improved my 5km pace quite a lot, I used to run 5km with a pace of 6 min/km and today I&apos;ve managed to reach
a 5min/km pace. I&apos;ll prepare to run for a half marathon within 4 months.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1&gt;Side Project &lt;em&gt;Architecting&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My side project environment will probably be over engineered, but I personally hate working on poorly engineered projects. Therefore, if I want to stay sane, deployment and project setup needs to be as clean and seamless as possible.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I want to create a side project environment where all my projects can talk to each other via a VPN, I want the deployment of all my nodes/side project to be as programming language agnostic as possible. I want to minimize cost, ideally I
don&apos;t want to pay more than 20-25cad, up to 50cad dollars a month for the whole thing. Self-Hosting would probably be the &lt;em&gt;cheaper&lt;/em&gt;
option although that&apos;d would also be the more time intensive and since I value my time, self-hosting isn&apos;t really an
option.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The pretty obvious setup I&apos;m thinking of using is having a managed Kubernetes instance deploying docker container, the
pipelines should be pretty simple too since the core thing they have to do is build the docker image and publish it to
a repository, which also implies I need a private repository for my docker images.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So it seems I&apos;m gonna need the following to run my project:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Managed Kubernetes Instance&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Container image repository&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;A managed postgre SQL instance maybe?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;</content:encoded></item><item><title><![CDATA[Finish the Week with Something - Week 8]]></title><description><![CDATA[Summary I've reached the goal I had set for myself back in August of 2020 which was to reach the Master Division in Starcraft 2. I started…]]></description><link>https://jeanarjean.com/blog/2021-05-16-finish-the-week-with-something-week-8/</link><guid isPermaLink="false">https://jeanarjean.com/blog/2021-05-16-finish-the-week-with-something-week-8/</guid><pubDate>Mon, 17 May 2021 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><content:encoded>&lt;h1&gt;Summary&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I&apos;ve reached the goal I had set for myself back in August of 2020 which was to reach the Master Division in Starcraft 2. I started running again.
I am setting new goals for the future.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1&gt;Starcraft 2&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I accomplished my goal wednesday, I had set for myself the goal of reaching Master in SC2. It took me 9 months, I kind of wanted
to start working on something else at times but I couldn&apos;t give up on my goal, I too often give up on things thinking they don&apos;t really matter, but I wanted to prove
myself I am able to become on of the best at something that is really hard, and I did. I think it&apos;s one of the hardest thing I&apos;ve
done in life, like I could run a marathon, but that&apos;s a race against myself, it&apos;s not a 1v1 game, the dynamics and mentality are quite different.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I don&apos;t know if all the philosophy I had towards the game actually mattered, it seems the day I reached master, I was playing with the only philosophy that I was
going to win and reach Master that day, I had a few thoughts of failure, but I still managed to make it. On the final day, I reached
4200 MMR for the first time, and then I reached 4300 MMR for the first time and when I reached 4330, I was promoted to master. I guess before that day, I thought I couldn&apos;t beat 4200 MMR and
upwards players but during that day I beat very very good players with 400-600 MMR higher than mine. My worst matchup before wednesday was Terran vs Zerg, but on that day, it was my best matchup. It&apos;s
like a door had suddenly unlocked and I knew how to beat zergs every game. I took the right decisions, saved as much of my units as I could, and made the most out of my hellions which I
used to use use passively. It seems my time practicing playing zerg might have shown me how zerg works. I could make better decisions because
I knew this. I used to see zerg as this big
unstoppable force, but now I knew how they wanted to play, and I could play around that, push them out of their comfort zone,
make them do stupid mistakes.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I tend to win games where I&apos;m active on the map, where I can pressure the opponent and make him commit mistakes,
staying back usually is a pretty bad option. In TvP, it&apos;s kind hard to have a
presence on the map passed 3 minute mark and before you have stim researched, since stalkers and adepts are so good against reaper and without stim marines and marauders are trash, maybe going cyclone would be a good choice? &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I think I played for 4-5 hours straight on the final day, I used to think I couldn&apos;t do that, I used to stop playing as soon as my brain sent signals to stop,
I sent signals to go back to my comfort zone, but on wednesday, I pushed past this fucking comfort zone, into greatness. I should do
this more often.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;MMR progression through the year&lt;/em&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;./mmr.png&quot;&gt;
Data provided by &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.rankedftw.com/team/478340/#td=world&amp;#x26;ty=c&amp;#x26;ra=best&amp;#x26;tyz=0&amp;#x26;tx=a&amp;#x26;tl=1&quot;&gt;rankedftw&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1&gt;Running&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Also started running again, I ran 10km at a 6:35 minutes/km pace, it took me a while to recover but I believe it was worth it,
I then ran a 8 km run at a 6:00 minutes/km pace which wasn&apos;t too shabby either.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I don&apos;t know if I&apos;m going to start running again, I like biking too, actually I prefer biking, but my god damn bike always seem to be breaking
so it pisses me off to bike.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1&gt;Future Goals&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Now I need to settle on a new goal, many opportunities present to me, I could start a business, I could help people by doing volunteering
work, especially website related ones since it something that not everyone can do, I could grow my print business, that would involve creating a SERIOUS following on instagram, since I don&apos;t to annoy my closed ones with posts begging them to buy my work
on facebook, and if it&apos;s only people I know buying the fucking prints, it ain&apos;t a fucking business, it&apos;s a god damn charity.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Starting a print business, would involve a shit ton of time spent on instagram, maybe money on ads, taking pictures that people like&lt;br&gt;
instead of street photography pictures which no one seem
to want on their wall, I guess urban stuff isn&apos;t very very inspiring on your wall. There doesn&apos;t seem to be an alignment between what I want to do and what they want to buy.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Conversion on instagram is also questionable. How the fuck do you build a following on instagram, I have no fucking idea, I guess you post regularly and you do collabs, you build a network,
maybe create/join an art collective. All I know is that solely posting pictures on Instagram doesn&apos;t cut it. When I shared a post about having new prints for sale on my website, I got a single visitor from
instagram out of 200 followers. It seems I&apos;d have a shit ton of work to turn this into a successful business, which is fine, but I don&apos;t know if instagram is the answer.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I feel like taking more pictures of people, just bringing my camera everywhere, always having it on me (actually wearing it, since otherwise I&apos;m too lazy to take it out of my bad). I want to document life, not just
the street, everything.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I&apos;ll give myself a week to set a goal, right now I&apos;m thinking of setting a entrepreneurship one and fitness goal &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Entrepreneurship/Side Project&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Photo Business&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Start a SaaS&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Make an indie game&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Get involved in volunteering&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Physical&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Run a marathon in a year&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Bulk up for the first time in my life at the gym, maybe have target lift weights I should achieve in a year.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Bike a long ass journey somewhere in a year&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My programming philosophy has been getting pretty stale lately, I&apos;ve been stuck in the C# and javascript world for a while, seeing something
new could be really helpful, I also should push my understanding of reflection in C# further.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And I also need to read more, I&apos;ve read a lot last year, but my thinking has been also pretty static, I don&apos;t have as many new ideas
since I&apos;m not reading as much.&lt;/p&gt;</content:encoded></item><item><title><![CDATA[Finish the Week with Something - Week 5]]></title><description><![CDATA[Summary The two last weeks were failures programming wise, I didn't work on side projects related to programming although I wanted to, I did…]]></description><link>https://jeanarjean.com/blog/2021-04-26-finish-the-week-with-something-week-5/</link><guid isPermaLink="false">https://jeanarjean.com/blog/2021-04-26-finish-the-week-with-something-week-5/</guid><pubDate>Tue, 27 Apr 2021 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><content:encoded>&lt;h1&gt;Summary&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The two last weeks were failures programming wise, I didn&apos;t work on side projects related to programming although I wanted to, I did however work on a goal I have set back in August 2020 which is to reach the Master division in Starcraft 2 in a year.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1&gt;Starcraft 2&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When I decided to reach master division, I was diamond 3 and at 3400 MMR, which is approximately 900 MMR from my goal (the Master division starts at around 4300 MMR).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; I ended last week at 4066 which is 250 MMR from my goal which isn&apos;t too bad, although the higher MMR I have, the harder the enemies I face, therefore the closer to my goal I am, the harder it becomes.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;One thing I have certainly noticed over the past few months is that my abilities to play Starcraft 2 well
is very dependant on two things. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For one, how much mental energy I currently have when I play the game strongly affects my play, I&apos;d estimate the effect of playing when my mental energy is low to affect my play by around 300 MMR which means that if I&apos;m usually 4000 MMR player, when I play tired, I play at the level of a 3700 MMR player. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Another one is my philosophy of the game is at this point in time, since Stacraft 2 is a strategy the game, the way you approach the game can vary a lot, hence, by shifting my mindset and changing the way I approach the game, I can come up with new strategies and tweaks to my current strategies in order to improve my play. Starcraft 2 is a game of brains and brawns, on one hand there is a very high execution skill cap and on the other hand you also need to play around your opponent, react to his play, anticipate what he&apos;ll do and outdo what he&apos;ll do. Keeping an open mind and always finding new ways to overcome what your opponent is doing is key to success.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Progress&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As a I said previously, over the year my MMR has improved by around 650 MMR, the improvement has been far from a linear progression, there was a lot of inconsistencies in my play that can be explained by continuing to play on a bad days, or focusing on improving my skills and sacrificing wins in the short term in order to win more games in the long term. There are multiple ways to &lt;em&gt;crutch&lt;/em&gt; improvement, such as doing cheesy build order or using cheap shortcuts such as the F2 key in order to select your whole army. These crutches are what allow you
to artificially be a better player in the short term and sacrifice long term improvement.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;MMR progression through the year&lt;/em&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;./mmr.png&quot;&gt;
Data provided by &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.rankedftw.com/team/478340/#td=world&amp;#x26;ty=c&amp;#x26;ra=best&amp;#x26;tyz=0&amp;#x26;tx=a&amp;#x26;tl=1&quot;&gt;rankedftw&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content:encoded></item><item><title><![CDATA[Finish the Week with Something - Week 3]]></title><description><![CDATA[Summary This week, I've worked on my personal website, I released new prints that people can purchase. I also added added analytics to my…]]></description><link>https://jeanarjean.com/blog/2021-04-17-finish-the-week-with-something-week-3/</link><guid isPermaLink="false">https://jeanarjean.com/blog/2021-04-17-finish-the-week-with-something-week-3/</guid><pubDate>Thu, 15 Apr 2021 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><content:encoded>&lt;h1&gt;Summary&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This week, I&apos;ve worked on my personal website, I released new prints that people can purchase. I also added added analytics to my website which made it easy for me to track how many people visited &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1&gt;Prints&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I&apos;ve decided to manage the state of the cart manually using Redux, it was pretty easy to setup. I had to
use a cart as initially the website only let you purchase one print a time which didn&apos;t require any
state management. I integrate with Stripe, storing products ids in .env file. It&apos;s a lot of manual
work to setup a new print as I have to manually add the product ids in the .env file, and add the price
for the different sizes of prints.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1&gt;Analytics&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For analytics, I used panelbear, it was surprisingly easy to setup. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Setting up panelbear in a Gatsby website&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;deckgo-highlight-code javascript  terminal=&quot;none&quot;  highlight-lines=&quot;&quot;&gt;
          &lt;code slot=&quot;code&quot;&gt;// gatsby-ssr.js

const PANELBEAR_SITE_ID = &amp;quot;GETYOUROWNID&amp;quot;;

const PANELBEAR_CONFIG = {
  site: PANELBEAR_SITE_ID,
  spaMode: &amp;quot;history&amp;quot;,
  debug: false,
};

export const onRenderBody = ({ setPostBodyComponents }) =&amp;gt; {
  setPostBodyComponents([
    &amp;lt;script
      key=&amp;quot;panelbear-analytics-src&amp;quot;
      async
      src={`https://cdn.panelbear.com/analytics.js?site=${PANELBEAR_SITE_ID}`}
    /&amp;gt;,
    &amp;lt;script
      key=&amp;quot;panelbear-analytics-code&amp;quot;
      dangerouslySetInnerHTML={{
        __html: `
          window.panelbear = window.panelbear || function() { (window.panelbear.q = window.panelbear.q || []).push(arguments); };
          panelbear(&amp;#39;config&amp;#39;, ${JSON.stringify(PANELBEAR_CONFIG)});
        `,
      }}
    /&amp;gt;,
  ]);
};&lt;/code&gt;
        &lt;/deckgo-highlight-code&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Panelbear allowed me to determine instagram
isn&apos;t such great a channel for me, as I got a single visit from there where as I got a lot more
visits from my facebook post.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;./channel.png&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content:encoded></item><item><title><![CDATA[Finish the Week with Something - Week 2]]></title><description><![CDATA[I recently came across this 
Patrick Mackenzie article (aka Patio11) 
where he talks about finishing the week with something you can show…]]></description><link>https://jeanarjean.com/blog/2021-04-04-finish-the-week-with-something-week-2/</link><guid isPermaLink="false">https://jeanarjean.com/blog/2021-04-04-finish-the-week-with-something-week-2/</guid><pubDate>Mon, 05 Apr 2021 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><content:encoded>&lt;p&gt;I recently came across this
&lt;a href=&quot;https://training.kalzumeus.com/newsletters/archive/do-not-end-the-week-with-nothing&quot;&gt;Patrick Mackenzie article (aka Patio11)&lt;/a&gt;
where he talks about finishing the week with something you can show people in
order to build a huge body of work over the course of one&apos;s lifetime.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is week 2 since I started doing this, I didn&apos;t end up finishing what I was working on during the first week so
there&apos;s no first week post, but I&apos;m hoping to publish something here every week in order to showcase what I&apos;ve done.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This week I opened a &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/crsnbrt/keysim/pull/51&quot;&gt;pull request&lt;/a&gt; for &lt;a href=&quot;https://keyboardsimulator.xyz/&quot;&gt;keyboardsimulator.xyz&lt;/a&gt;,
keyboardsimulator is a Three.JS application to test out layouts and keycaps combinations for keyboards.
I wanted to test keycaps on a layout similar to the upcoming GMMK Pro,
so I created a layout similar to the GMMK Pro, I also had to program the render for a knob which is part of the
GMMK Pro and needed for the layout to be complete. The color of the knob is changeable in the case options panel on the left.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h5&gt;GMMK Pro Render&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;./black_2_1000x.png&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h5&gt;Keyboard simulator 75 Knob Layout (similar to GMMK pro)&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;./PRPreview.png&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Comments and feedback are appreciated at &lt;a href=&quot;mailto:arguinjr@gmail.com?subject=Extern%20Alias%20CSharp&quot;&gt;arguinjr@gmail.com&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content:encoded></item><item><title><![CDATA[How to Use Extern Alias to differentiate assemblies with the same namespace in C#]]></title><description><![CDATA[If your project contains two assemblies with identical classes and namespaces, you won't be able to differentiate them unless you use extern…]]></description><link>https://jeanarjean.com/blog/2021-03-10-how-to-create-alias-property-in-your-csproj/</link><guid isPermaLink="false">https://jeanarjean.com/blog/2021-03-10-how-to-create-alias-property-in-your-csproj/</guid><pubDate>Thu, 11 Mar 2021 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><content:encoded>&lt;p&gt;If your project contains two assemblies with identical classes and namespaces, you won&apos;t be able to differentiate them unless you use extern aliases. In order to use extern aliases, you first need to open the .csproj file of your project. And then modify the PackageReference or ProjectReference by adding the &amp;#x3C;Aliases&gt; attribute.&lt;br&gt;
If you&apos;re referencing another project in your solution, your .csproj should look like this:
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;deckgo-highlight-code xml-doc  terminal=&quot;none&quot;  highlight-lines=&quot;&quot;&gt;
          &lt;code slot=&quot;code&quot;&gt;// Project.csproj
&amp;lt;ProjectReference Include=&amp;quot;..\Example.Project\Example.Project.csproj&amp;quot;&amp;gt;
	&amp;lt;Aliases&amp;gt;CustomNamespace&amp;lt;/Aliases&amp;gt;
&amp;lt;/ProjectReference&amp;gt;&lt;/code&gt;
        &lt;/deckgo-highlight-code&gt;
&lt;p&gt;or if you&apos;re referencing a Nuget then it should look like this:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;deckgo-highlight-code xml  terminal=&quot;none&quot;  highlight-lines=&quot;&quot;&gt;
          &lt;code slot=&quot;code&quot;&gt;// Project.csproj
&amp;lt;PackageReference Include=&amp;quot;Microsoft.CodeAnalysis.FxCopAnalyzers&amp;quot; Version=&amp;quot;2.9.7&amp;quot;&amp;gt;
	&amp;lt;Aliases&amp;gt;CustomNamespace&amp;lt;/Aliases&amp;gt;
&amp;lt;/PackageReference&amp;gt;&lt;/code&gt;
        &lt;/deckgo-highlight-code&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Then in any file where you want to reference either project, simply use the following directive to make a distinction between both assemblies.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;deckgo-highlight-code csharp  terminal=&quot;none&quot;  highlight-lines=&quot;&quot;&gt;
          &lt;code slot=&quot;code&quot;&gt;// whatever.cs
extern alias CustomNamespace

// You can then make a distinction between the two assemblies
// The one you used the extern alias on will be available through the specified namespace
using CustomNamespace::whatevernamespace.youwant
// The other assembly which you didn&amp;#39;t use the extern alias on will be available through the global namespace.
using global::whatevernamespace.youwant&lt;/code&gt;
        &lt;/deckgo-highlight-code&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You could also use two custom namespaces to differentiate the assemblies.&lt;br&gt;
&lt;em&gt;ProjectName.csproj&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;deckgo-highlight-code xml  terminal=&quot;none&quot;  highlight-lines=&quot;&quot;&gt;
          &lt;code slot=&quot;code&quot;&gt;// Project.csproj
&amp;lt;ProjectReference Include=&amp;quot;..\Example.Project1\Example.Project1.csproj&amp;quot;&amp;gt;
	&amp;lt;Aliases&amp;gt;CustomNamespace1&amp;lt;/Aliases&amp;gt;
&amp;lt;/ProjectReference&amp;gt;
&amp;lt;ProjectReference Include=&amp;quot;..\Example.Project2\Example.Project2.csproj&amp;quot;&amp;gt;
	&amp;lt;Aliases&amp;gt;CustomNamespace2&amp;lt;/Aliases&amp;gt;
&amp;lt;/ProjectReference&amp;gt;&lt;/code&gt;
        &lt;/deckgo-highlight-code&gt;
&lt;deckgo-highlight-code csharp  terminal=&quot;none&quot;  highlight-lines=&quot;&quot;&gt;
          &lt;code slot=&quot;code&quot;&gt;// whatever.cs
extern alias CustomNamespace1
extern alias CustomNamespace2

using CustomNamespace1::whatevernamespace.youwant
using CustomNamespace2::whatevernamespace.youwant&lt;/code&gt;
        &lt;/deckgo-highlight-code&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Comments and feedback are appreciated at &lt;a href=&quot;mailto:arguinjr@gmail.com?subject=Extern%20Alias%20CSharp&quot;&gt;arguinjr@gmail.com&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content:encoded></item><item><title><![CDATA[Free]]></title><description><![CDATA[Whoever must play, cannot play - James Carse, Finite and Infinite Games  Light Yakuza 0 spoilers ahead, nothing major The third chapter of…]]></description><link>https://jeanarjean.com/blog/2020-06-11-freeeee/</link><guid isPermaLink="false">https://jeanarjean.com/blog/2020-06-11-freeeee/</guid><pubDate>Fri, 12 Jun 2020 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><content:encoded>&lt;p&gt;Whoever must play, cannot play - James Carse, Finite and Infinite Games &lt;sup id=&quot;fnref-1&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#fn-1&quot; class=&quot;footnote-ref&quot;&gt;1&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Light Yakuza 0 spoilers ahead, nothing major&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The third chapter of Yakuza 0&lt;sup id=&quot;fnref-2&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#fn-2&quot; class=&quot;footnote-ref&quot;&gt;2&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt; is named &apos;Gilded Cage&apos;, the chapter begins as a rich entitled man is causing
trouble in a cabaret, the man thinking he can do anything. The man is interrupted by a young mysterious
man with an eyepatch, he is the manager of the cabaret, the manager handles the situation in an elegant way, he
plays with the man untill he gets him to admit his wrongs and pay the tab for everyone in the cabaret
that night. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This scene provoked a sense of admiration in me, the manager looked so nimble and agile, it seemed nothing
could bind him.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Then the cabaret manager is interrupted by another character and we learn that being the manager of the cabaret is a punishment.
The manager aka the protagonist has not choice but to be the manager of the cabaret, to redeem himself for his past wrongs. The mysterious
eye patch man has to make money through the cabaret in order to repay a debt indefinitely.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Reading Finite and Finite Game by James Carse&lt;sup id=&quot;fnref-1&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#fn-1&quot; class=&quot;footnote-ref&quot;&gt;1&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt; made me realize I was in a sort of gilded cage too, I made
the choice of going to college (I was strongly encouraged by my parents, but the choice was still mine to make),
this lead up to me accumulating a considerable amount of debt, I looked at college as something I had to go through
in order to live a good life afterwards, I was expecting to be free after college, to truly live the life I always
wanted to live.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Now I&apos;m out of college and I&apos;m currently employed, I feel a bit freer but not much, I still have to work, I have to pay
my debts, actually I guess I have the choice not to pay them and see what happens, but my mind sees the debts as
an obligation, something I must get rid of. I do feel trapped, in a cage, I work my shift and when it&apos;s over I&apos;m exhausted, it seems all my productive
energy is going towards work and I can&apos;t get out.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I want to live life freely, have enough money to work on what I want to work on, spending money on paying back my debt is what
I have to do right now, but what I actuallly want to do is save my money in order to be able to spend time in the
way I really want to spend it. I love my workplace and the people I work with but as James Carse has said, whoever
must play cannot play, and this is how I feel right now. I have to play and I end up feeling obligated to work,
obligated to perform, it is an obligation not a possibility.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Yet I refuse to see this gilded cage as an end, I refuse to do like I did in college where I saw it as something
I had to go through, something I really wanted to get over with, I don&apos;t want to tell myself: &quot;just pay your debt and life is gonna be
fine after&quot;. I want life to be good now, and that is a choice I can make right now, I can&apos;t always postpone enjoying life to an uncertain future.
I want to enjoy my time now, be nimble and agile although I&apos;m in a sort of cage,
make the most out of it, life is fragile and I have to enjoy sailing when the sea is still calm.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To making the most out of it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;footnotes&quot;&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li id=&quot;fn-1&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.goodreads.com/book/show/189989.Finite_and_Infinite_Games&quot;&gt;https://www.goodreads.com/book/show/189989.Finite_and_Infinite_Games&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;a href=&quot;#fnref-1&quot; class=&quot;footnote-backref&quot;&gt;↩&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id=&quot;fn-2&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://store.steampowered.com/app/638970/Yakuza_0/&quot;&gt;https://store.steampowered.com/app/638970/Yakuza_0/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;a href=&quot;#fnref-2&quot; class=&quot;footnote-backref&quot;&gt;↩&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;</content:encoded></item><item><title><![CDATA[Carpal Tunnel Syndrome, Running, Caffeine]]></title><description><![CDATA[I recently started developing wrist issues, my livelihood was pretty much on the line, if you spend 8 hours a day writing code, you
can't…]]></description><link>https://jeanarjean.com/blog/2020-06-06-carpal-tunnel-syndrome-running-caffeine/</link><guid isPermaLink="false">https://jeanarjean.com/blog/2020-06-06-carpal-tunnel-syndrome-running-caffeine/</guid><pubDate>Sun, 07 Jun 2020 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><content:encoded>&lt;p&gt;I recently started developing wrist issues, my livelihood was pretty much on the line, if you spend 8 hours a day writing code, you
can&apos;t afford to hurt yourself, you gotta fix your wrist or find another profession. After a life spent on education that ended up with me as a software developer, that wasn&apos;t
really an option.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I started acknowledging I was being negligent of my body, it&apos;s been falling apart for the past year and it&apos;s something
that really shouldn&apos;t happen to a 24 years old. I have a long lasting injury in my shoulder which I haven&apos;t managed to recover from and which
I haven&apos;t taken the right amount of time to fix either. I&apos;ve been negligent towards myself.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I decided to take actions, I had to give myself a chance, I knew I had to start doing more physical exercices. I took a small detour however
and decided to read &lt;em&gt;What I talk about when I talk about running&lt;/em&gt;&lt;sup id=&quot;fnref-1&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#fn-1&quot; class=&quot;footnote-ref&quot;&gt;1&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt; by &lt;em&gt;Haruki Murakami&lt;/em&gt; which I ended up enjoying
a lot, it was a calm book by a man with much more life behind him than me, it was interesting to see similar questionings from someone considerably
older. Someone much older who is according to himself living the life he wants to live. I ended up really appreciating his philosophy of life, of running by necessity to keep himself healthy enough to continue
writing, which is what he has decided is life is about. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So, I started running, I run at least 5km almost every day, sometimes pushing for more. Since I&apos;ve recently started running, I take a day or two off when
I need it in order to give my legs a chance to rest and recover. Rest usually makes a huge difference when I start running again, my legs are much more sturdy
and I don&apos;t feel worried of hurting myself at all.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I wake up at 5:30am, I usually run first thing in the morning, I put on my headphones and listen to an audiobook. Some people have told me they cannot even
imagine listening to something while running, for me it feels natural, it allows me to forget I&apos;m running and focus on listening. I also feel
like it might slow down my pace, I feel a lot faster while listening to music, but I&apos;m not running with a competitive mindset, I like pushing myself, but I don&apos;t care about not running the best time I can.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;One day I found myself programming for an hour or so after a run, without drinking any coffee.
At that moment, I realized that my previous stance on coffee, which was I need it in order to perform at work was completely wrong. I really didn&apos;t need coffee anymore. I used to drink
coffee all day and felt absolutely terrible when I wasn&apos;t drinking it, coffee also overstimulated me, it made me feel like I needed more stimulation than just working, I&apos;d end up
opening a thousand chrome tabs looking for something that would release a nice dose of dopamine in my head, I didn&apos;t want to live like this anyomre, I wanted to be able to focus on
things genuinely. Going for a run also made me realize that running woke me up naturally and that I could be focused on programming afterwards.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So I dropped coffee altogheter, it was a huge pain for the first few days, headaches and tiredness were commonplace, but then I started feeling much better. Now that the withdrawal symptoms are gone,
I can do deep work again, and I only need a run in the morning to feel awake. I am no longer dependant to coffee. It&apos;s been three weeks now, I&apos;m very very happy about the decision,
I am much healthier and the decision has already paid off in my opinion, but I&apos;m sure it will be even more important for my health as/if I get older.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I&apos;d say, the truest thing about all this dropping caffeine thing is that I don&apos;t feel much different, if anything it made me deadly bored, unexcited, don&apos;t get me wrong, I don&apos;t regret the decision, it brought me back to reality.
Lack of stimulants have brought me back to a peaceful life, a boring one, one which might be the envy of many, yet being in it feels horrible. Life has lost its lust, it is plain, there is nothing to be excited about.
Getting rid of stimulants made me realize that maybe the life I&apos;m living right now is due for major changes, that right now I am not very very happy, that it is in my power to make it happier and this is actually
something I&apos;m excited about.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;footnotes&quot;&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li id=&quot;fn-1&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.goodreads.com/book/show/2195464.What_I_Talk_About_When_I_Talk_About_Running&quot;&gt;https://www.goodreads.com/book/show/2195464.What_I_Talk_About_When_I_Talk_About_Running&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;a href=&quot;#fnref-1&quot; class=&quot;footnote-backref&quot;&gt;↩&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;</content:encoded></item><item><title><![CDATA[Why I Write]]></title><description><![CDATA[There's this innate feeling to some people, probably most people, that they're
not doing enough, they're not meeting their expectations.
I…]]></description><link>https://jeanarjean.com/blog/2020-03-26-Why-I-Write/</link><guid isPermaLink="false">https://jeanarjean.com/blog/2020-03-26-Why-I-Write/</guid><pubDate>Fri, 27 Mar 2020 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><content:encoded>&lt;p&gt;There&apos;s this innate feeling to some people, probably most people, that they&apos;re
not doing enough, they&apos;re not meeting their expectations.
I have this feeling, some people might call this being ambitious.  That&apos;s actually probably
the word I&apos;m looking for. Ambition makes me feel like I can achieve great things, it also makes me feel like
there&apos;s a lot of weight on my shoulders. The crushing weight of all the things I should
be doing, but I&apos;m not doing or haven&apos;t done yet. Ambition makes me feel like I have a lot of potential
that is not beng lived up to. Potential is a loaded word, as soon as you acknowledge the fact that you have
potential, pressure sets in. You have to live up to this potential or
accept the fact that you won&apos;t meet them and be forever disappointed in yourself.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What makes me think I have potential is simple, I have a relatively sharp brain, good health,
pretty good work habits, a good upbringing and a lot of free time. I spend a lot of time reading or working
on side projects. I absorb information. I absorb a lot of information,
but I don&apos;t take the time to share it, I don&apos;t
either take the time to fully &lt;em&gt;ingest&lt;/em&gt; the information, which means I might absorb
it but I get no use out of it. I don&apos;t take the time to master it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I might have the potential I think I have, but I don&apos;t live up to it, I avoid living up to it, I get interested in many things but I don&apos;t focus. I&apos;ve noticed that while having quite a few interests is very fun,
it dilludes your ability to be truly great at one of them.
I&apos;ve been avoiding focusing too much on anything, &lt;em&gt;keeping my options open&lt;/em&gt;, but also not living up to any expectations I have of myself.
Not deciding to focus on any one thing. Today I&apos;ve decided to take the first
step, I&apos;ve decided that my focus would be programming.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;On another note, I&apos;ve also been avoiding sharing the information I absorb because I&apos;m afraid I don&apos;t master it
enough to not look dumb when I talk about it. I also want to hold myself accountable for what
I choose to learn, engage myself to master the information I absorb in order to be able to share it afterwards.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1&gt;Focus&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So I&apos;ve taken the decision to focus on programming for now, or at least for a considerable amount of time, I want
to focus on one thing at a time (this is an idea from Steve Pavlona &lt;sup id=&quot;fnref-1&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#fn-1&quot; class=&quot;footnote-ref&quot;&gt;1&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;). I figured I&apos;ll be able to get better at things this way.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Strategy&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;!-- ## A LEVER TO MOVE THE WORLD  I LIKE THIS --&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;What is a strategy&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;According to Richard P. Rumelt, a strategy has three distinct but complementary parts.&lt;br&gt;
This is directly taken from the book &lt;em&gt;Good Strategy, Bad Strategy&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;sup id=&quot;fnref-2&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#fn-2&quot; class=&quot;footnote-ref&quot;&gt;2&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;br&gt;
A strategy is:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;A &lt;em&gt;diagnosis&lt;/em&gt; that defines or explains the nature of the challenge.
A good diagnosis simplifies the often overwhelming complexity of reality by
identifying certain aspects of the situation as critical.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;A &lt;em&gt;Guiding Policy&lt;/em&gt; for dealing with the challenge. This is an overall
approach chosen to cope with or overcome the obstacles identified in the diagnosis.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;A set of &lt;em&gt;coherent actions&lt;/em&gt; that are designed to carry out the guiding policy. These are steps
that are coordinated with one another to work together in accomplishing the guiding policy.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;The Diagnosis - What is Going On&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I&apos;m spreading myself thin, I won&apos;t be able to achieve what I want to do if I lack focus&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I don&apos;t have any serious outlined way of sharing what I do.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I read a lot, I learn a lot, but I don&apos;t apply or share what I learn&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Guiding Policy&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Focus on one thing &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Share my progress here to hold myself accountable&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Coherent Actions&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Have a clear focus every week with time set aside especially for it.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Write a post a week to keep myself accountable on mastering what I focused on or learned this week.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Risk&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;Too much of one thing&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Right now my focus is programming, which is also my job, I might burn out if I spend
all my time doing the same thing without getting rest.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;Risk Mitigation&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A good way to mitigate this risk is to make sure I get sufficient rest time even if I spend
time programming outside of work.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Reflections on the Strategy&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I don&apos;t know if the premise of the mentioned book applies well to personal growth, but my current
methods aren&apos;t taking me where I want to, a change of focus is then in order.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;To move in one direction, you must forgo all others. To choose one goal is to forsake other possible goals.&lt;/em&gt; - Mastery, George Leonard &lt;sup id=&quot;fnref-3&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#fn-3&quot; class=&quot;footnote-ref&quot;&gt;3&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;footnotes&quot;&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li id=&quot;fn-1&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.stevepavlina.com/blog/2008/12/rapid-improvement/&quot;&gt;https://www.stevepavlina.com/blog/2008/12/rapid-improvement/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;a href=&quot;#fnref-1&quot; class=&quot;footnote-backref&quot;&gt;↩&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id=&quot;fn-2&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.goodreads.com/book/show/11721966-good-strategy-bad-strategy&quot;&gt;https://www.goodreads.com/book/show/11721966-good-strategy-bad-strategy&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;a href=&quot;#fnref-2&quot; class=&quot;footnote-backref&quot;&gt;↩&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id=&quot;fn-3&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://sivers.org/book/Mastery&quot;&gt;https://sivers.org/book/Mastery&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;a href=&quot;#fnref-3&quot; class=&quot;footnote-backref&quot;&gt;↩&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;</content:encoded></item></channel></rss>